If you don't know the Lion Dance meditation very
well, you can record it. You can bring your
phones,
and we're going to turn off the air conditioning.
In this system, the people in the back are
dying of heat, and those in the front are
dying of cold.
[Music]
So, if you're not recording, please
turn off your phones.
We're not going to do a slow-motion
Lion Dance; we'll definitely take a
break in the middle.
[Music]
Many people weren't here during the
long walk, so there's
a little more explanation. Okay,
please. Your nose might run. You
need napkins; here they are. So, there's
clear air in your throat.
Please don't clear your throat during
the meditation. Let's
begin.
[Music]
So, the Lion Dance meditation
begins like this: do
n't focus on any noise in the
room, like the air conditioner
or the heater, the refrigerator,
the traffic noise outside,
children's noise,
or small noises in the room.
If you're inside a gaming cabin, you
can use more
subtle noises, like the sound of air conditioning
in the windows
with a kind of static in your ears.
Fix your mind on those sounds.
Don't
meditate for half an hour,
about 40 minutes. You can do that.  10
breaths in each step, it is
preferred to meditate for an hour,
you can do more or less 20
breaths per stage.
Ah,
so the first eight levels of the
Lion Dance are
not to overcompare
the previous stage with the next, and
always seeking to reach more stillness,
more silence,
and it is also a type of gacha. I wanted to express
gratitude for
leaving the noisiest level to
enter a quieter level.
It is a
very active comparison as soon as
one level increases to another. So
we go from the noise of the air
conditioner to the first level, which is the
noise of the heart. Let's compare
the heart with the air
conditioner.
Compared to a noisier place to a
quieter one, we consciously
choose the quieter place and
move away from it.
So compared to the refrigerator, we were
with the air conditioner.
What is this? The
world in which we live, the
realm of desire. We choose the realm of the
heart, which is a much
quieter place. Now move towards the
heart. Stay in the heart. First
level, it is
the realm of form,
very much so that it is
not really the realm of form.
You focus only on the heart, as
with your meditation
in your life, as a meditation in Bogota
will be reincarnated.
Yes.
The meditation, 30 of the companies
reincarnated in a world of superheroes,
for example,
but when the karmic credit
of that card runs out,
99% of those people always go to
the lower realms.
So we don't want to dedicate all the
meditation to these stillnesses,
but we want to reach some kind of
content,
and content that works in our favor,
for you.
But to do that, we have to go through
all the
stages. More silence, images, and noises
are quieter.
Don't dedicate your life to meditating
only in silence; it doesn't end,
the dying process doesn't end.
So let's go to the heartbeat.
Basically, go back to the air
conditioning or the air from the fan.
Then use it as
a focal point,
but in science, sound. And then go back to the
topic
of form. So in this room,
distractions can be used to
climb, to go up to the next anniversary,
second level of the realm of formlessness.
We try to imagine that instead of
seeing the heart from the outside,
we enter the heartbeat. In
technical terms, it's moving
from avoiding, each time, going
to deeper levels. Deeper
breathing,
yes,
silence. Excuse
me, imagine being, imagine entering a
room where everything  It's beating,
and that situation is much
quieter than seeing or hearing the
heart beating from outside. We
become one with the heart.
At the
third level,
classically, we release every sensation of
pleasure
with the measure, with the posture of the
object's migration.
I like to imagine the heart
now beating
a little further away from me, as far away as possible, like
in a void. In
fact,
I don't relate much to the
Latin American stand on its own, as it's
distant,
and so it's
almost canceled.
So imagine the heartbeat
in the hallway, imagine a void, as we do
n't connect with it, we don't relate to it; it
just beats,
and we enter a deeper silence
that is inside the heart. At
its
fourth level, the realm of form is
characterized by
a high level of a single point of
focus.
Basically, we release all sensation
in the body, especially
the pleasurable sensations of the good
position. With attention,
know your body. It has been in this state that
the sensations arrive,
and the mind focuses like a laser on the
single point. Once I
know it's difficult to reach a point
of focus, then think of something
small
and put your mind  In it, that helps a lot; you
can focus
on concentrating. So we use
a grain of sugar in the fourth level
of the realm of form—
a single grain of sugar floating in the
darkness,
crystalline white,
famous—
and we move the mind within it
and definitely release the sensation
of the body.
These are not antidotes for samsara;
these are not going to solve the
problems of your day,
nor the problems of your work or
your family, or the problems of
mortality. But we are climbing the
ladder to a point where we will be able to
face those problems.
Now we are going to enter the first level of the
realm of formlessness.
If we only meditate on these four
for a long time in your life, you
would be reincarnated in a place where there is
no great suffering. You also wouldn't
have a physical body,
and I saw that it is like that for a very long time.
And then when you die, you will
always go down into the lower realms
because you have used up all your karma.
So we don't stay in this meditation; we
only use it to move upwards. It is
called
accessing yourself. It
means... Now we show our
flexibility in limits,
right? A grain of sugar to a state of
passion.
So let's imagine a great lake
in our  The mind is like the surface
of the side
and it's on a horizontal plane.
It expands to the left and to the
right. Especially, let's say
we're going to jump a little ball in the center
of the lake.
The waves will
go to one side and to the other.
I like to think of it as a single wave. It's the
highest it can be, two and a half centimeters
high. I find it
very beneficial. If I think about it, the
movement is very quiet. It's
much quieter and deeper in its
focus than a grain of sugar.
We increase our
mental flexibility from a point of focus, a milestone
towards the expansion of the entire universe,
and yet, each time, we achieve more silence.
What we release is the little ball,
and we see the wave moving away. Once,
don't let it stop. And so,
if you happen to lose focus,
keep thinking about getting the little
ball back, and keep thinking about the expansion
of the wave without any cost, or
expanding infinitely.
Now, in the center of your mind,
for my purposes, darkness.
And it's a point in the middle of a
room.
We have two meters above floor level, in the
center of your mind.
And we're going to a quieter place
called the second level of the realm of
form,
and we're going to imagine that we turn on the light,
and that...  Light bulb,
if the light, according to Villa, expands in
all directions,
and that light isn't yellow, it's clear light, and
again, it's not the meaning of
already, like a crystalline color,
which doesn't mean,
like in Buddhism
[Music],
but we imagine a crystalline light
expanding from a point
of a light bulb,
and I would like to think that it expands to the
size of the Earth, and then it expands so far beyond the
heart of the sun,
then that illusion to the stars, and
then beyond all the stars,
the universe has an infinite number
of planets. Somewhere right now there are
other people meditating like
us,
many countless places,
are in meditation right at this
second, the second level in the kingdom of
reform. I like to imagine
Christ,
I like that this light that was
expanding overlaps, sticks at some
point, sticks with the light of other people
meditating at this same level.
So when I say let's
learn about health
and let the crystalline light
expand
infinitely in all
directions like a ball,
yes,
light is your consciousness of your own
mind. Now let's learn the light,
don't let it  Stop, don't stop.
At the same time, try to become
quieter and quieter inside. A
picture of the lake.
The third level in the realm of form, the
7th of eight levels,
counting air conditioning as
0. This is called Chi and Me, and we just
try to imagine that we are going to turn off the
mind, like turning off a switch.
Thoughts and
feelings are simply
turned off.
When I say "let's go," we are going
to close the mind. If
any thoughts, sensations, or memories return,
push them out
internally.
In absolute silence,
quieter. A previous realm, we are going to
turn off the mind now.
Fourth level of the realm of
form, and the highest
of the eight levels of meditation that we
are using to prepare our
minds for the meditation itself. So
these eight levels are not real meditation;
they are just mind stretching,
mind warm-up for
meditation.
This is not meditation.
[Music]
These cannot help in your day in a
real way.
[Music]
In this last realm,
but your whole level—sorry—
the mind is turned off, but when the
thoughts and
sensations come back, we surrender. We let them in. We do
n't make a sound when trying to...
Pushing them out like we did
the previous level is a
quieter place, super quiet,
where we simply surrender and
turn off the mind. But if it doesn't turn off, we
simply let it go. We do
n't maintain total silence; we don't
resist. We simply let the
sensations and memories pass.
[Music]
3. Excellence is: don't open your eyes yet. You ca
n't open your eyes.
Stretch. I know.
[Music]
Prepare the microphone.
I have a question about this first part.
[Music]
We'll start the second part in a few
minutes, but anyone who has a
question about
the first part,
thank you for coming. I have a question:
During the instructions, when we're
moving from one form to the
next, when you're giving the
instruction,
and my mind was jumping around, that's
a good question. Genesis question
from Janis: When I'm watching the
instructions, should I be starting in
meditation? I don't have to start.
The reason I extend the
instructions is so you can
learn meditation.
So when you do it on your own,
use the recording. Follow the
recording, and then you can stop
using the recording, and then you simply
decide to go up on your own. And it's always a
process of comparison. I
know the level in  The one you're in is
fine, it's quiet, but it can go even
quieter. Then look
to the next level, and that one will be even
quieter. There's supposed to be,
once again, an emotional feeling of
going deeper and deeper. And
for me, it's like drilling inside,
not just getting used to that
silence, and then not asking, "Can I go
deeper?" And it goes deeper.
When you listen to a recording, it's very
difficult to go deep, but you
imagine it. So it's important to say that you
have to practice a lot to
really go through all these
levels. I'm describing them;
you're imagining them. But
when the real thing happens, the whole
process is much deeper. There are no
more sounds, no distractions. You have to
practice. It's
like learning a sport or learning
a language; it takes time. You have to
practice every day. Even
if you can't do it for a long time, if you can't do it for
an hour a day, you can
go through all these levels much
faster. You have to go to work, do
everything much faster,
okay? When I say five breaths at the
beginning and then move,
that becomes a distraction, but you'll get
used to the timing. Of course,
there are different versions
regarding how many breaths there are
between each level. There's
a  The version has 20 breaths per
level.
At the beginning, use your breath to
count roughly when to move from one
level to another, but eventually, you have to stop doing
that too because it becomes
a noise or a nuisance.
Another question:
thank you for the teachings. During the meditation,
my mind tends to think about things instead
of focusing, and there's more agitation all
the time, especially at this eighth
level. It tends to
come to my mind not to think, and
that goes against the trend, and
then I get frustrated
during the meditation and during those processes.
And many times when this
meditation ends, I feel very tired because I've
tried so hard to keep my mind still. It's
not very peaceful
because my mind tends to think about
doing things.
So what do you suggest?
Perhaps I should know that
at the beginning,
your mind, the human mind, is very
active. Stanley's mind is very active, so
to make the mind
listen to you is a struggle. The M&T, who
wrote the best books on
medicine, cameras, and lenses, how many did he
write about three pounds a man in
Tibetan?
We have read
when you read the first two
cameras, chilies,
king, nothing,
the Kabbalah, and it comes from  In those books, it
says that it's very common for a
person and a lama to ask, after
teaching meditation, "My mind
got worse,
and my mind is only quiet sometimes.
Now when I meditate, it's very noisy,
worse than before."
[Music]
And then the meditation manual says, "
Your mind was always terrible until you realize it.
Understand, you understand
now. You are listening to the mind, that's why it
feels worse."
[Music]
There's a stage in the first six months
when you feel frustrated and
integrate. It was worse. You are
learning to listen to your mind.
For the first time, it's that
bad, and it was always that
bad, but you never realized it
because you were always inside it and didn't
learn how to observe it. So,
being inside the mind, being
inside your thoughts, and learning to be
inside your thoughts is
different.
All our lives we have been
inside our thoughts, very
busy thinking, talking, talking,
talking. Now we begin to observe and
say, "Thanks to our mind, it's getting
worse."
In reality, we are only
learning to observe it. Then we will
learn to control the mind and make it
quieter. So there is a  I've been
starting out, and it's tiring, it's a
battle against the mind. My suggestion is
just so you don't get stuck on images,
go quickly to the 8 levels and enter
level number 9. The idea of ​​the
first 8 is to do exercises and
build your mental muscles.
And I like to say that your mind
is like a dog, like a bad dog,
and you have the dog on chains.
We have a dog that we also
badly create, a small, active,
black dog, and it always wants to leave. You
push the little one, but it pushes to
leave,
and then you have to grab the jar,
but it wants to think about food. In my case,
thanks to the Americas,
yes,
the mind always wants another place. You have to
say, "No, no, come here." You have to
pull the rope and create the mind as if it
were a dog,
and then think of something else and try to
go back, since it will bring it back.
Every time you bring the
mind back to its place, this muscle, this
levitation muscle, becomes much
stronger. So in
Buddhism, the battle
is tiring, but it's something good.
If we call the territory, the
mind is tiring.
[Music]
the May  These are two three-year retreats in a
row.
She can tell you, it's a battle.
People come in halfway through the cabins.
When they read
after three years, they saw the
inside of my cabin and said something similar. It seems
peaceful in here.
Yes, yes, as if the
Vietnam War were peaceful. Many battles have been
fought in each of the
battles, every time, in each of the
cabins. So don't expect
meditation to be peaceful.
Even if we do wrong, it's still peaceful.
But if you're really looking at your mind, it's
a battle. It does
n't happen the first time that you're going to
feel peaceful.
Perfect.
Someone turn off my alarm, please. We have to
fight. We have to battle.
Every moment you're battling
your mind, you're making progress.
And if you stay on the bench,
yes,
now I'm in nothingness. Everything is the
anthem. I'm not thinking about anything.
There's a name for that. It's called calling. It's
bad meditation.
If you tell me to meditate for longer than
you're capable of, you'll get there.
Most people, when they meditate,
should start with two minutes. Okay, it's
an old translation,
so maybe I can say more,
but if you try to stay there for two...  Hours,
you're definitely going to space before,
the mind is off, the mind isn't clear,
how good meditation feels. I
like to think that when you're watching
a good movie,
Guardians of the Universe, and you're
watching the movie and at the
beginning you're eating popcorn
and suddenly some actor is doing
something interesting on screen,
beautiful people, when the scene returns
and he's been
battling so much on screen and then you're
waiting for the special moment
where the green girl kisses the
handsome guy and everyone is waiting two
hours eating popcorn like
an American movie and suddenly,
a simple girl
starts moving forward
[Music]
and everything stops and with the popcorn
and everyone starts almost
trembling from the attention they're giving her,
surely she's going to give him a kiss after
two movies, they're getting closer
and everyone is
mesmerized, they've forgotten about the popcorn with that
focus, that moment in the
movie, what is that focus,
200, 300 people like this without
blinking, I mean, that feeling in a
good movie, that's good
meditation  That's what we want, it's not
just lying there.
99% of people who
meditate get like that, but true meditation
is clear, it's sharp, it's joyful, it's
engaged, it's excited or stimulating.
[Music]
If you're like that, then you're forming a
bad habit, you're harming your
mind, you're
doing future harm. Don't tell me to meditate for a
long time. Meditate for 20 minutes on
break, like we do now, and then
come back
when you're stronger. Then do more,
but don't do too much at the beginning; it's a
waste of time, and you'll create a
mental habit that's hard to change. Then,
any other questions? This is
n't for me;
this is
from someone in Vancouver, and their
question is: Sometimes when I meditate, I
feel things that are very scary. I
perceive them as fear. They may not
be real, but that's how I feel.
Is this normal? And how do I deal
with this?
And then
more. So, both
special, as I was saying, and they have
levels of dedication.
And the big turning point in how
I explain meditation,
the big inflection point in relation to
meditation, is when they are able to... [He
writes to a student of his,
and also wrote to the astro-
crippen
and said
meditation
is like seeds, some in...]  Your mind
listens to these thoughts all
day long, and the seeds are opening in
your mind. So let's do that
now. Next, in the next stage of this
meditation, you're
not actually the thinker. You're usually the one
listening.
So when you hear thoughts in
your mind all day long,
you're simply a witness. You're not the one
speaking, because the one who speaks went back
a moment ago.  He's already speaking, he
's listening. I like to
say it's like the light that comes from a
star,
the starlight you
saw last night, incredible, very beautiful
because it was right after the lunar new year.
Nothing,
the light hasn't been there for ten
years, much longer, but by the time the
light reaches your eyes, that star may have died. Because
your
thoughts have died, they're the same at the moment you
hear them.
The one speaking is already gone, so
you can't control the one speaking
in your mind, it's not possible. Okay,
people used to go to my mom, and when
I acted as translator, he would answer them,
translated from their English to English.
[Laughter]
People would tell him, "Rinpoche, I feel
pressured all the time, I feel depressed,"
and I would tell him the same thing,
and he would say, "What I have is some advice for
you
from far away: ask me another question.
You should be
happy
and then start doing your mantras
again."
[Music]
And that meant the interview was
over,
and then the other person would be waiting, and
I would stay. "
You're still here," Sula would say, "but
Rinpoche, you have serious problems, maybe even
suicidal thoughts."  I said what to
do, he says, "What
are you happy about?" And
the person would leave angry
and depressed, and then I would go up to his
room and ask him, "Why are you
saying that to him? Is it because it
helps him?" And he would say, "Because it's very late.
The seeds are planted and the seed
is opening. They are listening to
a star. The activity is over. It's very
late.
You are going to be depressed today, but you won't
be depressed next week. So be
good to other
people, be kind to other
people.
I hope you plant a good seed this
week and next week when
your seeds open, they will be
nicer thoughts." Meditation is the same. You ca
n't meditate, you ca
n't control your mind. You are going to
hear what is heard from the
seeds. You will hear something quiet,
or maybe you will hear something noisy,
but by the time you hear it, it is
too late.
With K, he said, "You can't push a tree
back to the ground." The person who invented
Vipassana—I took that course when I was
20—you can't push a tree back
to the ground. To the seeds,
then, the real thing, the real point
with meditation is not to distract, not to
bother other people, to make
other people be  Happy to make
other people, other real people,
calm so that next week
when they plant those seeds, their meditation
will be peaceful. But you can't control your
meditation because the light has already left the
star. By the time you're
listening, it's too late. Understand
the real issue with meditation:
not to distract other people's minds, be kind to
other people's minds, be
happy to be peaceful.
Next week, your mind will be
peaceful. Or did you understand? I've
forgotten what the question was.
So, if you get scared and strange
images appear in your meditation, those
images were planted the week
before. It's too late to stop them.
[Music]
Remember the stars
that are 100 million light-years away. It's too
late. You have to
deal with the seeds
in your mind. You have to use the four
steps to cleanse the bad seeds
and avoid making people nervous or scared.
And then those thoughts won't come up again
in meditation.
If they keep coming
[Music],
if they keep appearing, it means you're not being
good to people, you're being
bad to someone. Okay,
let's do the second part.  shovel then
we do we answer your question and
second part is usually the nose
[Music]
stop your phones
this is the second part of the
lion dance then we're going to take a bathroom break
so you can meditate on your bladder if
you want ok we're going to meditate on it for a long
time
[Music]
so we're going to pretend we just came out of the
last level of the realm of
forms
we turn off the mind
yes
and when the thoughts came we didn't
confront them
now we begin the real meditation
the ninth floor is the real
meditation the first 8
including level 0 which is the air
conditioning are not
meditation they do
n't contradict
the way the mind normally sees
reality the earth
the world
now bring to mind one of your
teachers in your life it can be your mother or
your father who are your first great
teachers it
can be a sample of your on every occasion it
can be
a football coach of some sport it
can be a spiritual teacher
like a parent or a rabbi a monk you
can think of our historical figure like it can
be doubts with Jesus
but months later
I took Gandhi
your heart is particularly good
because he has helped you because that person
who  It helps you more in your life, it's
especially important,
and for some of us,
if we haven't yet found someone we
can consider a heart-shaped figure,
then you can imagine
a perfect image of your heart and
create the three centers for
you
in meditation. Right now, this
is the beginning of level 9. I
advise you not to make it an
image or something imaginary, but to
feel it as something real. It's not a statue; it's
a person breathing, a warm body. These are
the teachers sitting
knee to knee, their
eyes closed, their
eyes open,
looking with so much love, so much affection, and so
much emotion, so
happy that they are making the
effort of meditation.
Oh,
and then there are many qualities of
your teacher's heart that one admires,
and surely there are many of those
qualities that one would like to develop
within oneself. That's why these
people represent a teacher. That's why
in this level 9 meditation, one chooses
one of those qualities.
This person's heart could be your child's, or
someone who said their
motto was "root,
your dog, and I believe him." So think
of a good quality
that one admires in a person. You can't
change the person from one to another.  From the
meditations each day, or you can stay
with it for 45 days and then
change it to others.
As you do
more and more, you will find much
sweeter qualities in these people. It's
very useful
to focus on a negative quality in a
person and meditate on it. It does
n't improve your mind, it doesn't make you a
better person,
so I ask you to choose
an admirable quality from those people.
So now choose the
quality.
Ah,
now go back to the center of your
mind, which is where we have been
meditating.
For me, I imagine a dark room.
Half of the room, let's imagine a
small nest, like the nest of a spaceship, and
inside there
are 67
silver eggs,
as if they were in a light that
shines on them, and they are very bright,
very beautiful.
And now imagine that one of those eggs
opens,
the shell cracks,
and an image comes out of it,
a very small luminous image,
perhaps the size of a mechanical ball,
and it comes out of the essence of the egg.
As you can see, it is a hologram,
and it is the image of your quality, of
your teacher. In my case, let's say that  I'm
thinking about what
calls to me,
the consideration that calls to me, I have
for people.
So I imagine an egg that is worshipped
in the center of my mind.
An image of consideration comes out
in my meditation. It moves, as if across the
front of my head.
New images emerge from my head
and settle on my lama in front of
me, like a layer, a covering, a
paint, and it covers them.
And that's why I see
consideration in me. It's more like this,
more comfortable for you.
Think that the seeds come out of your
heart. If you tend to get
nervous in the meditation, you can
imagine that almost thousands are coming out
near your spine, at the
level of your navel, and that's going to make us
feel better.
And what matters most at
this level of meditation is
this feeling, this sensation of what you
are seeing in your master
quality.
In my case, consideration
is a gap where
seeds come out in my mind.
Those seeds open and bring out images,
and those images cover my lama. And
that goodness that you see in my lama comes from
those seeds.
Think about that,
then go back to the second egg. Look at
how it appears
in the image coming out
of...  Turn around as it settles on your lama, and
that's the second moment
of consideration. Then return to the nest
and repeat this process for a few
minutes. In real life,
this happens
at a rate of 65 seeds or eggs, 131 per
second.
What we do is like in slow motion.
If this part is done correctly, you
should have a sense of
shock and beauty. I
see you realize
that my teachers come from
me.
Perhaps you don't see Aqualia in myself,
seeds to see the one from another person. Ah,
now let's take a fun trip.
Let's imagine what I might have done to
plant those seeds. So, I must have done something.
If I see something in my world,
a quality in my teacher, it has to
be that I planted it
before,
in this life.
But let's pretend
what we can do, even in past lives. And
let's imagine. Try to imagine something we might have
done in the past to
plant those seeds.
And be creative.
Be happy. It
was something very nice, very good that you
did in the past, a very good
habit that you
have maintained for a long time. As
many people have tried,
be imaginative. Don't get stuck
on any image that comes to
mind.  Because each of those images
that appear belongs to you,
your seeds.
Any story you can invent
about your past, well, from your own seeds,
may not be correct, may not
be exact as it really happened.
Perhaps the future
one may have passed correctly,
but right now, let's make a
story, let's write the script of a
movie about our past. It
can be in any era, thousands
of years ago, when I was in China, in India,
in Europe,
or in pre-Columbian times in
America.
How I treated people, what I did
day by day, what
made me plant these seeds
so that now you see a lama so
considerate.
Well, write your movies,
okay? Just a few breaths, then we'll take
a break.
Now, go back to the lama you have in front of
you. Do
n't you have
better feelings and better ideas about
why you see your lama in that
polite way? Move aside.
And now imagine
another image of yourself that looks very
similar, and just like you, but this one
is like a second husband in your kitchen.
This second
imaginary image of a
good flame doesn't come from me, and it doesn't
come from my seeds.
If I don't deserve it, it's
not because of things I've done.  Good to
other people is simply an
accident I bumped into this lama by
chance by accident that does not come from
me there is no history between
us two in the past
of past lives there is no
future in which we have
a grand happy ending to this story there is no
future together there
were no futures together
we are not in enlightenment hand in hand it is
simply an accident I
bumped into him by accident
and I got here by chance
and they are here by chance if you do not
follow this way of thinking
everything is random I meet people
randomly there are
no past reasons for this
until the very universe itself
lines of a random explosion called
the de Tang
and some dust particles are
hit and hit against each other
for millions of years until
finally they have stuck together and now
has produced my nose if the nose of
look at me in the eyes of Milan have made
this world
that is not a
coincidence in the West
I like to call this lama you call
my mind my accidental lama
with my random lamas
the big band
and try to have this image of this is
a mess this this
is incomprehensible that it is so
exquisite it is
not a  Stopping is not an accident, it's
not true that we don't have a future
together, but we have a happy ending.
What else has happened to me? Many good things
together
are coming from these seeds.
But I don't believe this idea of ​​an accidental lama.
So I cleanse
the most accidental or false one. I bring
back the real one.
Keep in mind,
the place where the real lama is
sitting
is where the false lama
was before, and that's to take care of. Without
a city, I ca
n't see this lama coming from
seeds. So practice the feeling
that lama
exists
in space. It has been
left
when we canceled the accidental slam,
which is our lama living in the
city.
33 exhalations,
then open your eyes, stretch,
then I'll answer questions. We're going to take
a 15-minute break.
I think there are some green juices and
fresh juices for you in the kitchen. That's why
for me, the green juice is
immediately below
the yogurt, which I detest. So maybe
at your dealers, and you get the green juice. I'll see you
in 15 minutes.
Oh yeah, okay.
So we're going to go, we're going to
go into your heart,
your diamond ass. About the end,
we're going to go, we're going to go.  Let's see your
meditation schedule,
yes, yes,
here,
first
Mayan type,
based area,
but the dance
snap down
video, there will be, bye,
2, okay, you
wake up,
so we are in Caracas, what does
star mean?
We said there would be six
different meanings, I'm going to review the first
three,
the first was, you were
talking about sharing with the bed, the
former island
on the milk plateau,
and it's that stars can only
shine in the darkness,
in your understanding, the
darkness represents that we cannot
understand the object,
and then the stars
represent bad things in our lives
because we don't understand them, we don't understand,
and then even if we understood, they would continue
as if the sun came out.
[Music]
We used the example of your husband or wife,
someone got angry because we always used
the words "husband" as a problem,
when
at home they yell at their children, then they
get home and their husband
criticizes them, yells at them for some reason, and they
have two options, at that moment, they
can understand
that husband comes from those
silver eggs in their mind as their lama, or they
can say that they don't say anything
and they are hurting me, they are bothering me
if they think that you don't say anything before,
that's like the  darkness,
and then he,
the husband, is like
darkness. So a Buddhist man,
a Buddhist person, has to change
the seeds. The good thing is that
telling the husband that we are
changing, one simply changes him. You don't
need a long discussion for
your husband to change. You can change them,
but that doesn't mean that 19.
That means that eating to comment on the
suffering and mistreatment of another.
If he is not hurting you, you don't have to
be there still to say to
yourself, you
have to take action. You have to
look for something.
If things get worse, you have to
seek this legal help. Of course, you have to
do what you have to do, but you have to
understand
that if that works, it doesn't only depend
on oneself. There shouldn't be any seeds in one's
eyes. You have to
seek help.
Here in this place, we have a
very strict policy. Every time one arrives at the
signing here, no alcohol, no
drugs, no weapons, no
harassing another person
sexually or physically. It's a policy
here for
14 years,
and we have a process
in case something like that happens to you and
you want to report it. You have to talk to
someone on the committee. Can
the people on the committee please stand up?
Michael Steele
[Music]
John Brady and the list:
if you have any problems, please
report some of them. If you're shy,
you can write an email to us; it
can be the same. There's no
need to say who you are. We have a
system for investigating any
kind of problems,
and that issue of seniority—14 years—I've been
on all the committees. We've
investigated, we've
acted,
we've disciplined, we've reported
these people to the police. So if you think you have
a problem, feel
free. Sometimes someone
visits an old problem;
you can also count them.
But the stars come from within, which does
n't mean you don't tell the
committee or call the police. What it
means is that you shouldn't get angry
because you don't understand where they come from. You can't
fix them
by fixing your own seeds. That's the
first step.
The stars are the truth of
suffering.
When the sun appears, which is the
direct perception of emptiness, those
stars are no longer seen.
The people who are going to take care of me can't
see suffering directly.
In fact, they can no longer accumulate bad karma;
they can only continue to experience
bad karma that blossoms, but they can't
generate bad karma for their next life.
There's another way to interpret this:
Emptiness
allows things to appear, so
for him
darkness is not ignorance, it's
for care.
We finish a meditation where we tire,
where we cancel the false lama, we
cancel it as an
empty screen is offered, we cancel it in the
maxillary and that gives rise to the
true lama of the projector, which is
called our mind. Do you understand?
Darkness
is emptiness and allows things to
appear, like the stars. That's why
for him all things are
appearing
because emptiness allows it. I think
of a white screen,
which is emptiness, and then your mind is
the projector,
and then the images you put into the
projector are the minds, that's what you're going to
see.
If there hadn't been care for the screen, you wouldn't
see images;
if there weren't an empty, dark space, there would
n't be stars.
Let's go to the fourth one. Then
the same lama says, "Then
darkness,
the first example
in the diamond workshop, can
exist or not, it was to
exist or not. Now,
darkness, good or bad, in this
case,
then I'm going to interpret not understanding
something as something good,
it's good." He said
you can think of darkness as something
good or bad
when we talk about interpreting 1000
Misinterpreting
the Jewish character is a bad thing,
but you can also think that
darkness is something useful. That's what's on the
screen; it's emptiness. It's
something good. That's the fourth way to
understand the stars and the darkness. He
says, "So you
know, you can think
that darkness is bad, something bad. It can't
start with that it's something good, okay? And
if you want to go deeper,
that's the emptiness of darkness. It
sounds good to some people and
terrible to others. So
darkness can be misinterpreted,
or darkness can be
emptiness, even good things.
That's
the fourth interpretation."
The fifth, then, comes
from an area they call
so famous, so famous that sometimes, if you
consider it the second most important, it's called the
second most important.
One of the first great areas,
when we finish the cameras and we're going to
start, his most famous book, which is called
Wisdom.
Always read those books, a longer
root text, which are the verses of
Wisdom, but we give Wisdom
a very beautiful poetry,
and it's like
taking a walk through the kingdom of
Judas,
haha.
So
I think it's going to take me two or three years to
see all that poetry. I've never seen a
good translation of that book, okay?
So they don't fill in the blanks. He wrote  He wrote many
poems, but he also wrote commentaries.
Among other things, there is a famous one, the
famous prayer
[Music].
In that region,
the most typical offering is to imagine that the
sky is covered with flowers and that one
offers oneself to one's teachers. It is
part of the "chupa" and of George's book.
He wrote a commentary on that
book;
this is it.
And then he writes a commentary about
the stars appearing in a glass of
water
if it comes out through the...  Night,
and if you don't have a bucket of water
and you can't see the reflection of the
stars on the surface of the water,
he says that the meaning of
the stars is illusion, that
the stars are meaningless
because one can see the stars on the
surface of the water, but they are not the
real stars.
If you have a program where you just use your
iPhone on the surface of the water
to see the stars, it won't work.
By the way, have that program because
you point it at the stars and it will give you
the name and the history of the stars. It's
very interesting. It's
number 52.
It says that the stars represent
illusion because one can see the reflection
of the stars on the edges of the water,
but it's illusion. 6
is simply common sense.
The stars
don't last. Every 12 hours, okay, they disappear.
Until one can say the sixth
meaning of the word "star" is that they are
permanent, they always go, they always
disappear.
One of the
most famous questions about these verses and
the story is whether it's talking about
impermanence
or illusions because
one of the nine metaphors
seems to be talking about permanence,
but some seem to be
clearly talking about illusion. So
there is one  Great question for over 2000
years.
Is this [ __ ] talking about impermanence or
is she talking about illusions? How would you vote
for this?
Would you be voting for both? I
agree with
this one only, but they are both.
Every morning the stars disappear,
like our relationships, like our
money, like our lives, like our
bodies.
Well, in that bad,
but it's also an illusion, okay?
And that illusion depends on the darkness, on
not understanding.
Yes,
so we're talking about the EMT. It's a
number 20.
[Music]
The first three,
the tests, 3 is like the universe. The
first
three describe ours, our world.
Yes.
[Music] We
know we have.
Now let's go to the second one.
If earth, yes,
look,
three roots here, three separate roots.
There are three roots transcribed here,
and in one of those, city, okay.
The root of this word is seen in Russian
and means line. It means that it
cannot be given blindness.
The second week, rice, means that it will be
cut off at the root.
[Music]
And a place in a city that is set
apart for worship
or a temple is called that. The same root
means clear, it means cut off.
What do you call a particle?  that cannot
be divided, that
is, that is the root of cutting
in the third meaning, so that it is fear, fearful,
shy, lives off of that.
So have the second
example of, look, I am alone, I am blind, and I
am afraid, it is
that I am isolated, I am afraid, I am
blind. That is the root,
and that in this case means a
cataract in the eye, it is
an extra layer of skin on the eye that makes
you blind, that makes you... Now I am going to give you six meanings, six different meanings for the cataract, six different meanings for this layer that covers the eye, like the base, band, zone, and lama. It is also said that the important interpretation is that you
believe there is something there that is not really there.
[Music]
Because of this layer that you have on your
eye, you want to see something out there that is
n't out there. It is simply a layer of
skin on the eye, it is simply a
problem in your eye. It
is the second meaning;
it seems as if it is there, but it is really
a problem in one.
Okay, do you understand?
The interpreter sounded famous from "Chimera." The
cataract,
always and well, I always saw it well in two
categories:
one, you see people and you see things
that you don't have; you see people and you see
things that aren't there.  There, your husband is a
person,
but
if you go into a place with traffic,
someone called me and said, "I'm going to be
late, filling up Tucson, no, because of
traffic, because of traffic problems,
and traffic problems between Tucson and
Puig."
[Music] You
could tell me that in Berlin or
Shanghai, but come on,
traffic problems on Google gives less
next time, okay?
But traffic problems also come
from oneself, don't blame the traffic,
don't get angry in traffic, the purpose
of studying, having the center of the
diamond treasure, is to stop
being angry
about things, it's us, it's a
problem in our own eye, don't get
angry at people,
not just at things, both things
come from one,
so second interpretation,
yes, he
likes to talk about the truth of
suffering, I
like to talk about the fact of
suffering because it refers to
suffering itself, you
can tell him, you can tell him the 4
facts, the 4 facts, you can
say that if you have a
defective instrument, it's that there can be
suffering from the world, okay?
He relates the sight to the
truth of suffering,
an area, a person who is looking at
emptiness.  They can't directly
perceive suffering; it's not possible.
So for him,
the skin covering the eye, the
cataract, is gray suffering.
And if you don't see the cataract, you wouldn't see
suffering. An area can't see
suffering while they see the third city. On
the 16th, let's talk about 80 Kirti. Let's talk about
entering the Middle Way.
A very famous book of the city,
the Middle Way, the Book of Art Facts,
is Gardiner's Book. Okay, it
's the most famous book. They awaken
in it. It's
the most recent book of the city,
years old. And if not entering the Middle Way, but in this case, it refers to the book called Wisdom on the Name of the Book by Gardiner, okay? In that book, he says [Music]. He's talking about a famous example from ancient times for the things that one
sees are coming
from oneself. And the example is
like when I take a shower in the bathroom. You
can see, I
always leave 30-40 hairs
on the white tiles.
You see, you can see that if I don't clean
the hairs, 60 Kirti says, but
some  Some people say they have
a crack in their eye,
and they don't try to clean it, but they can't
because it's an injury to the eye,
a scratch.
So, in the third interpretation
of the damaged, defective eye, it
says that one sees what one has the
capacity
to see,
and that is the first law of karma. What
is the first law of karma
for the week? What
the eye makes you see is
what you
see. A hair on the porcelain is because
there is a small injury to the eye.
And a new husband who yells is
because you yelled at the children
last week. You have the scratch in your
eye.
You said
the content of the illusion
comes from how you treated people
last week or last month.
They understood
the type of blindness, the type of problems you
have in your eye. It decided what you see
if you are annoying or yell at someone.
So next week, the hair
you see in the bathroom, which is actually a
scratch in your own eye, is going to
show you the
same thing as last week.
When you talk about the effect of an effect on
your eye,
you...  Let's see, the same thing
that's going to be the same as
last week, you're
always going to give the same ones that existed
last week, yes, well, you said it, your
children, how cute they are, what is
your husband going to say
when he gets to the door, she's
very pretty, that's
a mother in your eye, yes,
good answers,
answer interpretation number 4,
comfort confirmation,
what does it mean
and what you want means,
what happens if a person with
clear eyes enters the same room,
during the room
at the door
and your husband tells you, you're stupid for
no particular reason,
okay, did you understand?
And then your friend comes in who just came
from cameras and the 4,
between the room, can you believe what he's saying to me, he's calling me
stupid? And your friend will tell you
who
is in front of you, it's my
husband who just called me stupid, he doesn't
see anything
[Music]
but where is this question, is he
hiding? He's not right there, but I don't see that, did you understand?
Someone who understands the third
diamond sutra and enters the page of just
with you, that is, I do
n't see a husband who is there who is
yelling at you for no reason, someone
who doesn't have the eye of the kitchen and
will enter  to the same place and not seeing the
husband,
what bothers you for no particular reason
is that fourth interpretation of the
eye problem,
then it's called confirmation,
confirmations that it's so crazy, a
person who isn't crazy comes into
the room with you, sees that they don't see a husband,
but it's your fault.
This is the
interview story I've had with each of
my students hundreds of times over
all these years. People tell me, "I
have a problem, nobody listens to me." Every
year I teach hundreds and hundreds
of people.
I'm going to buy a recorder, I'm going to
put it in my pocket, and it's going to say, "Maybe you
should try the four steps,
maybe it's coming from you." Do you
understand?
I can tell you that I talk to thousands of
people
and the stories are very similar: "My
husband, such and such," "I
've heard the four steps, but the
primary one is different." And I tell them, "The source,
tell me about your Maria," and they tell me, "
I don't have one, Carmen," and I know your
husband, so I don't have a
defective young one. You can continue when they come, "Well,
I have other injuries," but I don't
have the same injury that you
have in your eye. And if I can give you a
comment, a piece of advice, this is called
confirmation. A person who isn't
crazy  A person tells her she's crazy,
and they don't have an injury, they don't
have a defective eye, I don't know, is it
your husband? He seems like a good person, no, no, no, no, no.
And what do I say? Well, maybe it's a
problem with your vision. I think it's a
truth for the world, but not in my case.
That's the confirmation.
How many do we have for cataracts? Four.
Let's go to the fifth.
Two masters from our side were passing by. He
says, "Think about the wheel of life.
By the way,
how do you prepare for
how do you prepare to roll through life? That
's the reason why the
lioness meditation was designed,
Maitreya, that
is, in the lion meditation, and go to the
wheel of life."
[Music]
This dependence, okay. Now, generally
in the wheel of life,
everything is mixed up.
Every thing in life, the twelve parts of
life, is suffering. That wheel is about
the cause of the causes of
death.
So this is an important part
of the master going around saving. He says, "If your
equipment and your equipment of experimentation,
your senses, your eyes, nose, ears,
and if they were created by carnal, then
they are defective. Do you understand
that? It's very..."  Interesting,
your telescope has a scratch. Your
telescope, called your ear, your eyes,
have been built with a defect.
A normal person cannot see, hear, or
feel
without making a mistake.
Understand that it is in the nature of our
equipment that we are born with scratches on
our equipment. It is important to
understand that naturally,
the natural condition of
human beings is to misinterpret everything all the
time. Understand that it is
only with massive doses of
wisdom that we can ever see
something correctly
because we come out of the factory defective,
called
your mother.
We are born with it
because it has been produced in the closest way
to ignorance.
The blind person,
the person who has no training,
has to see things the wrong way.
So this is a very famous Buddhist thing. It is
not simply an error in
thinking; it is our
original equipment that is faulty.
With humans, normally, we come
from the mother. Five years later, we see
something and believe it comes from that side
because it is, because the eye is
constituted that way.
The same is with cookies.
With the cookies,
those cookies are sweet, but that
sweetness comes from within, not from the
cookie.  Your tongue is going to lie to you
because your tongue was born from
ignorance, it was born defective.
Your tongue thinks, "Wow, this cookie is
sweet," but that's true. But there's no such
thing as sweetness in the cookie; the
sweetness comes from you.
I had equipment that's faulty. That's
what Master says. Masters are saving you. That
's interpretation number 5.
Okay,
now for the good news. The 16th
isn't all bad news, and I'm sorry to hear them say "
Bordas" because of the warehouse.
Amen. And what do you have to learn? 6.
Say it, Borba,
and get
the Barba NCLR.
What it should mean is that it's
part of your mind that can't be
removed. It's like a cancer that's
spread throughout your body.
When they want to remove it, you're going to
die. You go to the doctor and tell him you
want cancer. You ask him, "
Can you get it?" and he says, "Jason,
metastasis,
Jason, metastasis. We would have to
rule out cutting your whole body open to
remove it. It's too late." Okay, it
's spread everywhere. It's part
of you. It's part of your body. It can't be
removed.
That's New Press.
Saying not to believe them
means
cataracts,
cataract metastasis. This can be
removed without destroying your eye. It's not
possible, okay?
Uruguay means
to be in front of your eye, and if you have
a good surgeon, you can remove it, you can
cut it, which is ignorance.
The second link, artist, is understanding
well, number 6.
Interpretation number 6 means
that the cataract in more parts is not
part of you, that it is removable,
okay? It has
n't metastasized yet.
You can still remove it with good
study, with good meditation, with good
teachings, with great effort on your part. You
can remove it, cut it,
and you can see things
correctly. Do you understand?
Because those are the six
interpretations. Let's move on.
Type
and long type,
progressive.
The word is type
in a verse. It has to change
depending on the text, depending on the
words around it.
The root of this word is easy.
The root is this type, and it is to shine
on the tongue. The pile are interchangeable. It
comes from divine type, from
many names, the gods in
ancient days, the paths of heaven.
Jupiter comes from that.
Jupiter wants to be me, Peter, the form, the
ancient form, Peter.
Father of light,
exalted, let us surpass
Jupiter, father of the sky, and many names
of the gods are, make Tuesday good in
that, if you are the day of the day of the god
with which is called
the god that shines,
this was divine of you, oh god or deity,
pardon,
if you Jupiter, Joe, they
all come from the same root, view, that is,
a lamp that shines,
now our change, the Chilean, by the way, has so many
interpretations, 6,
also
the first base, sides,
says
about the paste, so much, all is the same,
to make a lamp of butter as
the mint of here, you need two things,
one you need the wick,
and if you need something else, that you need
the butter or the oil or the wax,
you need two things to make a
lamp, you need the wick,
that generated fabric, and you need a
fuel, something has to feed the
wick so that it lights,
what is the fire, it is your
samsara consciousness, the consciousness of samsara that you were
born with, that comes defective from the
factory, your defective perception, the light
of perception, the light of consciousness,
that light
that comes from the lamp, so your
lamp is your
consciousness of what it means.  wick
karma
this is cameras and the pavilion
means karma
represents the butter or silk or
oil
[Music]
rue of the way number 8 which means
while of all my coffee
still drink the coffee
and you want money because you have
money
so we have more money through
representing ok
from Guangzhou
and you have you are an option for
taxes are the reports are the
reports nobody finds out ok the interest
gives you cash cash is the
return for a service in the US you
have to pay taxes but don't
think well nobody knows about this this
income of money so I'm going to
spend the money use the money I don't have to
pay taxes on this do you understand
then that attitude that desire
awakens the seed of karma
misinterpreting or not understanding where
the money comes from
and the desire that comes from that
misinterpretation awakens karma
which is the opposite of that
in a good seed that you awaken it
we're good to see
with coffee meditation rejoice over
a good seed is the butter is the
wax of the oil and the seed is the wick
in the case of good karma
ok the wick  It's giving money to someone
else, and the oil
with the fuel is from Georg,
doing your own thing, but not your own.
I did it, be happy
in understanding the glass, the side of
this text,
the lamp, the third example, the lamp,
the wick is karma, like being
generous with other people, giving
money to a person,
the oil, what ignites it is the
coffee meditation, having the correct
attitude in relation to that, be happy
for having done that, I'm happy to have done that,
with those two you get
fire, you make fire,
and with bad karma it's the same,
cheat your taxes, that's the
pavilion,
and then I'm happy to have done it like this,
now I have more money for myself, it's
in the way you see money,
and that's the oil, it makes your own, without
oil karma is not very powerful,
understand? They can make you a fire, but
learning will last a minute, it needs
fuel,
the fuel is misunderstanding
where money comes from, understand? Are you
understood by following,
okay? We
do this to suffering, he
says, the wick is the material cause, which is
a material cause
in things,
the thing that makes another thing,
what is
Maribel the material cause of a tree,
a seed,
now  We call a material cause
the seed becoming the tree, and what is the
contributing cause? Fertile water,
fertilization,
lack of insects that, like the
tree seeds,
understand for both means
cause, mind in the here and now, and wick. The
material cause of the flame is
Babylon. The
contributing causes are the oil,
okay,
and both represent
suffering. That's what the fire of
suffering does. Understand?
The word "cherche" revealed means
to spread
the cause, and your friend's house
caught fire in California these past few
weeks. 400 houses, 66,000 houses
burned in California.
These aren't cheap houses, they're
nice houses. These people can afford
fire insurance. What happened? What I
asked was,
the wind went up to 50 miles per hour. I went
up that kind of fire, a
reserve of the crown of some tree,
and it would touch the ground. You can't
stop it.
So, understanding number 2,
if you have the material cause of a
bad karma, and if you have the
contributing cause, which is being glad you did that, it's
the anti-
meditation of coffee. You're sad,
right? You're not kidding. I'm
glad I did it.  Knowing what you're here for, if you
had the chance,
that's a bad attitude about a bad
action. Machepa
tends to multiply, it has to
multiply, okay? So for him,
and we say this, the day is, the day is a
coffee, we offered,
we made many candles, it
took a very long time to make those
candles. What you learn quickly is that you don't
put them all together. Once
separated, if you put them all
together, in the end they all come together, the same
flame, and it burns in the house. Many people
have burned their house this way,
always standing on the line of
candles, because otherwise all the flames make the
moon
say that you touch me, so
that will have traps and
interpretations, okay? I'm
going to stop there.
Now, I
want to review your schedule
for today, and then I'm going to stop.
Ah, I
thought 10:00 to 10:30. Let's
continue, right?
Let's stop for 20 minutes. Okay, with
you, very good.
Understanding number 3 of the lamp,
this is a little more complicated. Let's see,
when we talk about the star,
we talk about the darkness, the
background darkness, which is emptiness, and that the light
That's all one really perceives when
looking at the stars.
To see a star, you need the
background darkness; in that sense, it's
emptiness. The background will just take
care of itself.  I am an advantage,
one can see the film,
so this is the screen, this is the
background screen, you are being cared for in
Buddhist terms, a lot of
emptiness, which is the background, and the
appearance of things that appear because of
carbon, that was the star
in a waterfall, we saw things
that couldn't be there, that was the
relationship, we saw things that weren't
really there.
When it comes to this, which is the lamp, he
says that the emphasis here is that what happens to you doesn't appear to you, it
seems to you,
the light of the lamp in this case
is taken out of the context of emptiness
and treated as something of one's own because I see
things, because I see people, it is the process
of the opening of the silver seeds
without referring to emptiness, according to
him,
because the word "appear" in Tibetan
is the same for the lamp,
okay,
with the technical word to make
the two types of realities a reality,
although he says the false reality because it
seems to you that it comes from this side through
the eyes, through
all the senses, your senses, the
defective factory goods,
this guy won't get off the shower, he didn't have
sexual purity correctly, no, but
he didn't bathe like that, that's the reason why
The thing that those who bathe
your nose reports that it comes from that
person but it doesn't come from you.
If you were respecting other
people's relationships all the
time, then everyone would take
showers, you understand? So
for me,
the third interpretation of lamp is to
emphasize the word,
the fact that things appear from
their own side.
[Music]
Thorton is the word for the, for an
area,
the words for those people, the
words in Buddhism, for not, for not would,
sorry, it is,
and a person who sees is from the outside.
This is what the president of
protection of lamp is, people who
see from the outside towards one. I
can advance,
this is difficult, but you like it
difficult, that's why what comes, we will
mountain,
this is a length,
things are empty but they work,
things are empty but they work. In
fact, one can say
sports,
things are
empty but still working,
things are empty but still they work.
If the causes and
conditions are there, they will work, okay?
In bs, and this means aspirin in your
language, it means, it means, in
aspirin
with the function of the spirit, to take it out of the
headache.
[Music]
What is  What's inside aspirin
that takes away the headache, what's it
called? It's the active ingredient, what's
the chemical name? It
slows down the transmission of pain signals.
A pain inhibitor is the
active ingredient in aspirin. You think
Canadian aspirin? You ca
n't trust Canadians,
but it works sometimes. Sometimes
means it doesn't really work. That
means they haven't found the
real cause.
Sometimes means it doesn't work. No, you wouldn't
get on a plane that sometimes
works and sometimes crashes. But you
take an aspirin, and if you take it, it
works sometimes, even if it doesn't.
[Music]
Which means the
active ingredient isn't actually active.
Sometimes it
should reach the
client. It's active
when an aspirin works.
What's the active ingredient in
our seeds? Our seeds,
because we helped someone who had
a headache earlier last week
because we have seeds of that pain inhibitor.
Because that inhibitor isn't the
active ingredient, right? In our
karma, it's the active ingredient, but that's
all.
He says, look,
and you can...
you... by the wick... by the
fire... it's going
to work, but...
but everything is...  Coming from you, everything
comes from you. It's empty from the base of
what?
To the emptiness of the active ingredient of the
odor inhibitor? Understand it.
When they stay very quiet, I think they're
not understanding anything. They're
fine.
Their seeds are what make the aspirin
functional. It's their seeds that make
the active ingredient
here.
There's a contradiction between the
city
for
emptiness. It gives rise to the lamp to be
made
in the locality. It means fire. The
fire isn't burning on its own.
The fire is burning because it
wants to. It's karma. There are
lower schools of Buddhism that say
what explains the fire. Part of the fire, they
say it's
moisture. It's part of the water. The
higher schools say who put the
moisture in the first time is fire,
heat. Fire,
how can you walk on water?
I know what it is.
If we believe those stories
are true, we believe that he
walks on water. He
understood the seeds. He talked about
seeds all the time. Is
there a problem with this Buddhism? And I think I
tell them,
look, Jesus talks about seeds all the
time.
Well, that's it.
The sign that they understand emptiness is that they are
more successful in their lives,
financially in terms  From
health relationships, they have lent salt
of mental state in the world.
These five things come from you, okay? The
sign that they are understanding
emptiness is that they can make
things happen, okay? It's
not this
that we are doing. This is
meditating. The care says that is a
sign of a person who is not
understanding emptiness.
A person who understands emptiness is
like the person in a movie, being
excited, being able to make
things happen, having a
fantastic life, things working out, going
well. They know how to plant the
seeds because they understood that
things are empty. They understood. They could, meaning
no.
If you are good
[Music]
he wants to make sure that you
understood.
He says that good things also
come from causes, in legal terms,
and in camera, it's row between camera months, it's
cinema, and he's going to talk about that. If we
get around to talking about that, in the
scriptures, the causes of samsara, in the
causes of Liébana, are the same, and the
principle is the same. The problems in
your life and all the successes in your life
come from the same principle, okay? The
causes  The seeds,
the oil, the wick, and the fire, okay, that's
number 5.
Good things and bad things
come from your own seeds.
Sixth,
number 5 is: good things come from
you, and bad things also come from you.
And in terms of these,
we would always say
with "d" it
means the circle, suffering
in the same principle as ultimate good
in ultimate evil, well, the same
principles,
where by the way
the correct pronunciation is "to become
samsara,
samsara," you'll
see.
And it's not a big wheel of life out there far away.
Tell me the moment,
the moment when
suffering begins
in the wheel of life is when a
replanting. The boys are bad in the
flames, stupid.
You hear yourself planting the
seeds, the females. If next you
get home, you meet your
husband, your husband yells at you, "You're
stupid!"
At that moment you can stop the
blind man, how can he keep doing it? How
can you keep following him?
It's an essential good. Don't think it's in
Xares,
rebirth, blah blah blah. One makes a
replanting sit a hundred times a day. Your
reaction to problems is
being the rope back.  to the circle
of life
[Music]
I don't know why my children are badly
behaved
and I don't know why my husband calls me
stupid for giving a
particular reason if that's the case that makes you
think about the root of the son sara and the root
of money wins are the same has the
same principle the lamp type
to sing this morning ok grab the
procession well
bojan
usually iron can sing the morning
in that same state
it's horrible because if it stays in your
head you
hear these people singing and you
can never forget it again it sticks
in the brain
ok
and well then we're going
to do it after the meditation
because before the meditation this brings a
lot
and then later someone is going to be
a version in Chinese zhan livorno
well it can be against
someone else
you can look for our gas
then we're going to learn Chinese and
Sanskrit I want to learn Chinese
when we have five because there is number
six
this is easy this is from management michael
there is a famous metaphor in fact he can
teach metaphors in school
he always says
life is a flame
if you say life like a
candle life is
a  Candela, what does it mean? It
means that they burn.
I know you see every minute. This is
impertinent. So the last
meaning of the oil lamp is
just remember that life is a candle. It's a
candle. Every second, every minute,
every moment is burning.
And it costs 65 per second, 25
instants, and it goes with a candle that keeps burning.
That's pretty obvious, but I'll mention them. Okay,
yes,
we've covered the three metaphors
and all these relationships, like we're
around, like our world, like
a star, like a waterfall, and it's like
a candle.
[Music]
So we finished the first group,
the first one. I'll leave it. We
finished the first of four. Now the
second.
There's only one in group 2: Maya. Wow,
the root of this word isn't clear
to anyone. Nothing is really certain.
It's checked. It
can be more than that, that you can go wrong
or go badly. It can be magic,
which means great power to
confuse you.
Magnificent. It
can be, well, you have it
there,
as it exists in English, which means
that it continues outside. It
can be more, since it means to go wrong
in any way, and the threads figured out the
whole thing, but wow, it means  Illusion
has two main meanings in
Buddhism.
Illusion can mean believing
something isn't there.
Classically, in the study of perception
and illusion, it can have many causes.
One is strong emotions—being very
angry or jealous—you're seeing things
that aren't there. Okay, so
strong emotions... I don't know, the movement of
things around you.
If you're at a traffic light waiting with
two cars on each side and suddenly they both
reverse, you wouldn't believe you
were moving forward, but it's an illusion, an
illusion of movement. It happens sometimes; it
seems like you have to brake
when that happens, but it's an illusion. You
reverse and believe it seems like you're moving forward,
and that confuses you. But
the second meaning of "maya" is "mute."
What's the name of the mother of Miami?
That means... It's not a magic trick.
I used an image of a
magician's hat and pulled out a rabbit. It's
the hat;
we're going to pull out an old coin.
That's what a magic trick is called.
So, "maya" means either of the
two.
When you're walking through the desert, with
water in the background and its illusions, or
a magic trick, "maya" can be
either of the two.
[Music]
Time there,
continue from there, I'm going to continue from there.
Tomorrow is quite hateful. I'm going to
give you
9 meanings of the illusion mesh. There are
no meanings, okay,
in the story. Now we're going to talk about how you're going
to meditate
today, besides sleeping. If you still have
jet lag, for
example, from the calendar,
well, you're supposed to go from here
and you're supposed to make breakfast
in your cabins. Veronica, I'm going to make a
big breakfast,
right? 11:45,
12:15 to relax.
We're going to meditate if you didn't have a good
rest. You slept well. It's not going
to happen. I did twelve repetitions
and it doesn't work. If you feel like you have to
sleep, sleep, okay? At any
moment
you feel like you have to sleep, sleep and
then get up and meditate.
Wash your face with cold water.
But if you didn't sleep well at night,
you have jet lag, then sleep,
rest.
Personally, if I have jet lag, we
normally have
no
rule.
Usually at airports, there's
transportation that takes me from one
gate to the other.
But if you have jet lag and you travel a lot,
stay awake until 9.  the
night and then sleep
ok but generally
if they haven't slept well they have to sleep
too I discovered that yoga is difficult
if they haven't slept well
the nickname of cleavage
s
include more is stored
that includes forever ask about
it
[Music]
at 12:15
let's see zinc
go to those three images of the
star the cataract the lamp
before
have a list of six words that will
remind you like like a pet a
machete
so you can open your eye and look from time to
time
so you can look at that little list
that have the class those qualities
try to remember their meaning
and then try to think of something real in
your life star
in the illusion
is my husband who has hurt me to be
[Music]
meditation should
link it to real life
simply philosophy think of the people
in your life who are like stars
think of times in your life that you have
had cataracts
understood think of things that are
empty but still work that
still work with the lamp like
aspirin
and then at 5:15 go for a
walk
[Music]
enjoy the sunset that  Here it's very
good to wear a hat, take
care of your skin,
use sunscreen. I'm
in the water
for the two meditations between 12:15 and
1:30, and for 4:00 and 5:00. You
can also practice the
first eight levels
and the ninth, but they arise, or do them
separately. Don't try to do the
Lion Dance all at once.
To separate it, tomorrow we will do the
first two parts of the Lion's Spear. We
will do it all together.
Today is very long, so
in either of the two
meditations, if you have a
warm-up with a little bit of the
Lion's Spear, it's very good.
Nobody walks through the desert without water, okay?
Never ever. Okay,
I have like a small bag hanging
on my shoulder and that's where I got water.
Keep a building in sight. I've
already gotten lost here. The path, I
walked for five hours, lost, I found
the houses, so,
and I've lived here for seven years, okay?
So it can be dangerous, so
always keep
an eye out. There's a structure, even a
reference point.
And I don't know what. When I started, when it starts
to get dark,
the snake likes the dark
because it likes being a snake. Why?
Because the mice have bad eyesight, it's
now, so
everyone is working at the same
time, everyone is moving, and so are we, so do
n't wait now, eh,
be careful where you step, never step in
the desert where you can't see what's
there. The only person who was
bitten by
a snake was from stepping on a log
without realizing it. Albino vipers,
if a viper bites you,
sit down and call someone. When you
start, when you start,
the venom in the blood runs faster
and it's worse, so stay still and we'll
take you to the hospital for an injection, and don't
worry.
[Music] You
hear a vibration, of course, don't look
from the sidelines and leave.
[Music]
They don't want you standing on
them, they warn you. Of course,
we are too big for them, they do
n't even want to spend money on
us. Not only that, but if we step on them, they will stay
put, but if not, they
are very peaceful, they have
a bit of an attitude, but
nobody in the desert bothers a
snake, it's something humans do. I
suggest you read the
Lion Dance  Before the
camera meditation, Cecilia
OK,
8:45 AM, 9:30 AM, gratitude for those who
have helped me in my life.
During our lives, many people have helped us,
and in our minds, let's give thanks. It's a
great coffee meditation. I like to drink
hot chocolate coffee. I like it. It
intervenes if you call, as very well, the
meditation cushions. I don't like to
sit on the porch of the house and see
the stars, and at the same time, with the mantras
you put in your minds,
I used to go to the roof to do mantras and
see the stars and see if I could find
satellites. OK, it's fun,
but it's millions of mantras
on the roof, Johnson. So go outside,
put on a sweater, put on a coat, and
see the stars. You won't see these
stars in other places. We are very
far from the cities, so enjoy
the stars. The most important thing is the
retreat. They are
free,
so
freedom.
Smile.
The same with meditation. They don't bring too
strong
the common email. The
most common mistake is that people try
too hard with the medication. You have to
be more relaxed. You can't do the
sub-20 if you are not very relaxed. If you are
very  tired is normal too
what